German Labor Union Pamphlets 6108
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
German Labor Union Pamphlets
1900-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Friedrich-Ebert-Stiftung
6108
25 cubic feet
25 linear ft.
Pamphlets.
Miscellaneous pamphlets dealing primarily with labor issues in West Germany and in reunited Germany after 1990.
3597012
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Colleen Kendell 6/99, June 01, 1999
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 23, 2016
Scope and Contents
Miscellaneous pamphlets dealing primarily with labor issues in West Germany and in reunited Germany after 1990.
Topics covered in these pamphlets include: collective bargaining; the economic conditions and policy of the Federal Republic of Germany from the period immediately after its founding through and after the reunification in 1990; environmental policy; the European Union and its predecessors; guest workers; postwar politics in Germany; social security; strikes and lockouts; training and education for workers; unemployment; wages; white collar unions; women in the workforce and in the unions; working hours; and works councils and other forms of worker participation in management.
Other organizations issuing these pamphlets include: Industriegewerkschaft Bau, Steine, Erden; Industriegewerkschaft Bergbau und Energie, Gewerkschaft der Eisenbahner Deutschlands, Gewerkschaft Gartenbau, Land- und Forstwirtschaft; Gewerkschaft Handel, Banken, und Versicherung; Gewerkschaft Holz und Kunststoff; Gewerkschaft Leder; Industriegewerkschaft Medien; Gewerkschaft Nahrung-Genuss-Gaststatten; Gewerkschaft der Polizei; Deutsche Postgewerkschaft; Deutsche Angestellten Gewerkschaft; and the Freier Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund.
Series I consists of pamphlets issued by the Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund (DGB), the large umbrella organization with which many unions in Germany are affiliated. Series II is made up of materials issued by a number of DGB member unions, including Industriegewerschaft Chemie-Papier-Keramik, Gewerkschaft Erziehung und Wissenschaft, Industriegewerkschaft Druck und Papier; Industriegewerkschaft Metall, and Gewerkschaft Offentliche Dienste, Transport und Verkehr. The pamphlets in Series III originate with such non-DGB unions as the Deutsche Angestellten-Gewerkschaft as well as with organizations like the Friedrich-Ebert-Stiftung and the Hans-Bockler-Stiftung that deal with labor issues.
Pamphlets originally collected by the Bibliothek der Friedrich-Ebert-Stiftung in Bonn, Germany.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5582: Archives Foreign File (AFF)
Labor unions -- Germany; Labor unions -- Germany (West); Foreign workers -- Germany; Collective bargaining -- Germany; Collective bargaining -- Germany (West); Employees -- Training of -- Germany; Employees -- Training of -- Germany (West); European Union; European Union -- Germany; Hours of labor -- Germany; Hours of labor -- Germany (West); Environmental policy -- Germany; Environmental policy -- Germany (West); Industrial relations -- Germany; Industrial relations -- Germany (West); Management -- Employee participation -- Germany; Management -- Employee participation -- Germany (West); Social security -- Germany (West); Social security -- Germany; Vocational education -- Germany; Vocational education -- Germany (West); Wages -- Germany; Wages -- Germany (West); White collar workers -- Labor unions -- Germany; White collar workers -- Labor unions -- Germany (West); Works councils -- Germany; Works councils -- Germany (West); Women labor union members -- Germany; Women labor union members -- Germany (West); Women -- Employment -- Germany; Women -- Employment -- Germany (West); Germany (West) -- Economic policy; Germany (West) -- Economic conditions; Germany -- Economic policy -- 1990-; Germany -- Economic conditions -- 1990-; Germany (West) -- Politics and government; Germany -- Politics and government -- 1990-; Deutsche Angestellten-Gewerkschaft; Deutsche Postgewerkschaft; Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund; Freier Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund; Friedrich-Ebert-Stiftung. Bibliothek; Gewerkschaft der Polizei (Germany); Gewerkschaft Erziehung und Wissenschaft; Gewerkschaft Gartenbau, Land- und Forstwissenschaft; Gewerkschaft Handel, Banken und Versicherungen; Gewerkschaft Holz und Kunststoff; Gewerkschaft Leder; Gewerkschaft Nahrung-Genuss-Gaststatten; Gewerkschaft Offentliche Dienste, Transport und Verkehr; Hans-Bockler-Stiftung; IG Medien; Industriegewerkschaft Bau, Steine, Erden; Industriegewerkschaft Bergbau und Energie; Industriegewerkschaft Chemie-Papier-Keramik; Industriegewerkschaft Druck und Papier (Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund); Industriegewerkschaft Metall fur die Bundesrepublik Deutschland
3597012
- Box: 1, Folder: 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: 80 Jahre Gewerkschaften in Hildesheim, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Author: Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund
    Format: Publication
    Language: German.
  - Item 2: Die A.F. of L. und die deutsche Arbeiterbewegung, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Allgemeine Erklrung der Menschenrechte, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Bericht des Deutschen Gewerkschaftsbundes Ortsausschu Hamburg, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: Gewerkschaftliche Wiederaufbauarbeit im Stadt und Landkreis Herford, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Fr eine soziale Demokratie, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Box: 1, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Gesetzesvorschlag des Deutschen Gewerkschaftsbundes fr das Gebiet der Bundesrepublik Deutschland zur Neuordnung der deutschen Wirtschaft, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Notes: 22 May 1950
  - Item 2: Der Gesetzesvorschlag des DGB zur Neuordnung der Wirtschaft, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Notes: July 1950
  - Item 3: Die Gewerkschaften in der Bundesrepublik, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Notes: 26 September 1950
  - Item 4: Die Industrie und Handelskammern, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Jugend und Mitbestimmung, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Dr. Rolf Fischer
    Notes: 21 July 1950
  - Item 6: Der Kampf der Gewerkschaften im Hinblick auf die Neuordnung der Wirtschaft, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Werner Hansen
    Notes: 28-29 July 1950
  - Item 7: Probleme des Mitbestimmungsrechts der Arbeitnehmer, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Box: 1, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Richtlinien fr die Angestellten- und Berufsgruppen-Ausschsse im DGB, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: Stellungnahme des Deutschen Gewerkschaftsbundes fr das Gebiet der Bundesrepublik Deutschland zum Wohnungsbaugesetzentwurf des Bundesministers fr Wohnungsbau sowie zum Entwurf einer Anordnung des Bundeswirtschaftsministers ber die Miethhe bei neu erste, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: 20 March 1950
  - Item 3: Die wirtschaftliche Mlichkeit zur Lohnangleichung, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: June 1954
- Box: 1, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Die Arbeitsvermittlung, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Author: Wilhelm Bergemann and Theodor Meyer
  - Item 2: Forderungen des Deutschen Gewerkschaftsbundes fr das Gebiet der Bundesrepublik Deutschland zur Wirtschaftspolitik, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: 12 March 1951
  - Item 3: Fragen der Sozialpolitik, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Author: Willi Richter
    Notes: 22-23 June 1951
  - Item 4: Frauen-Nachtarbeit?, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: Frauen und Mitbestimmung, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: Die Gewerkschaften in Wahrung Berechtigter Interessen, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 7: Gewerkschaften und Produktivitt, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 8: Gute Fahrt mit der Gewerkschaftsjugend, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 9: Das Mitbestimmungsrecht, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Author: E. Bhrig
  - Item 10: Mitbestimmung und Eigentum, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Author: Hans Korsch
    Notes: 11 July 1951
  - Item 11: Reaktion oder Neuordnung?, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Box: 1, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Rechtsgutachten, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Author: Kurt Ballerstedt
- Box: 1, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Stellungnahme des Deutschen Gewerkschaftsbundes zum Entwurf eines Bundesbeamtengesetzes, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Der Tarifvertrag, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Author: Peter Frhlich
- Box: 1, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Aufgaben Methoden Grenzen staatlicher Wirtschaftsfrderung, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 2: Auerordentliche Landesbezirks-Konferenz Bayern des Deutschen Gewerkschafts-Bundes, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Notes: 10 February 1952
  - Item 3: Getrennt sind wir Nichts, vereint sind wir Alles, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: Ernst Winter
  - Item 4: Grundzge des Betriebsverfassungsrechts, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: Kurt Thon
    Notes: 11 October 1952
  - Item 5: Mitverantwortung, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Box: 1, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Das neue Recht, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 2: Probleme der Rentenversicherung, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Author: Arthur Killat
    Notes: 25-27 April 1952
  - Item 3: Satzung, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 4: Stellungnahme des Deutschen Gewerkschaftsbundes zum Regierungsentwurf eines Gesetzes, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Notes: 25 November 1952
  - Item 5: ber den gegenwrtigen Stand und die weitere Entwicklung der Wirtschaft in der sowjetischen Besatzungszone Deutschalnds, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Author: Ernst Scharnowski
- Box: 1, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Vorschlag des Deutschern Gewerkschaftsbundes zum Entwurf des Gesetzes ber die Personalvertretungen in ffentlichen Verwaltungen und Betrieben, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Notes: October 1952
  - Item 2: Warum sind wir gegen die Remilitarisierung?, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 3: Wir Tragen die Zukunft, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Notes: 18-20 July 1952
  - Item 4: Die zeitgeme Bestimmung der gesellschaftlichen Stellung der Frau, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Author: Kthe Feuerstack
    Notes: 27-29 May 1952
- Box: 1, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: In eigener Sache, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: Hans vom Hoff
  - Item 2: Erklrung zur Wiedervereinigung Deutschlands, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 3: Der Gesellenausschu, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 4: Gewerkschaften und Betrieb, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: Erich Potthoff
    Notes: 23-24 January 1953
  - Item 5: Gewerkschaftliche Grundsatzfragen, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: Mattias Fcher
    Notes: 12 February 1953
- Box: 1, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Internationaler Mutterschutz, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Notes: 25 November 1953
  - Item 2: Das Ost-West-Problem und die Gewerkschaften, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Author: Albin Karl
  - Item 3: Richtlinien fr die Betriebsrtewahlen, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Box: 1, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Abnderungsvorschlge des Deutschen Gewerkschaftsbundes, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 2: Aktionsprogramm zur Angestelltenpolitik des DGB, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Notes: 16 June 1954
  - Item 3: Aktelle Fragen der Sozialpolitik, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Notes: 9 October 1954
  - Item 4: Die Angestellten in der Rentenversicherung, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: Otto Frhling
  - Item 5: Arbeitsrecht als gewerkschaftliche Aufgabe, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: Wilhelm Herschel
    Notes: 4-9 October 1954
- Box: 1, Folder: 14, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Du und Deine Gewerkschaft, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 2: Der Lehrvertrag, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 3: Muster einer Schlichtungsvereinbarung, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 4: Neuordnung der Rentenversicherung, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: Willi Reichter
  - Item 5: Richtlinien fr die Angestellten- und Berufsgruppen-Ausschsse im DGB, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 6: Richtlinien fr den Bundesjugendplan, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 7: Unsere Mitwirkungs-Hinweise fr den Berufsschulbeirat, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: October 1954
  - Item 8: Wirtschafts- und Steuerpolitik, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: Viktor Agartz
- Box: 1, Folder: 15, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Die Berufsttige Frau in der heutigen Wirtschaft, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Author: Ludwig Rosenberg
    Notes: 29 January 1955
  - Item 2: Bremisches Beamtengesetz, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 3: Neuordnung der Rentenversicherung, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 4: Frauen Suchen ihr Recht, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Author: Karl Baldamus
- Box: 1, Folder: 16, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Aktions Programm, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Box: 1, Folder: 17, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Gewerkschaft als Lebenselement der Modernen Gesellschaft, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 2: Gewerkschaftliche Beitrge zum Frauen-Lohnproblem, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 3: Lhne Preise Lebenshaltung einer gespaltenen Stadt, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Notes: October 1955
  - Item 4: Stellungnahme zu dem auf Grund des Brand-Gutachtens erlassenen Sofortprogramm der Bundesregierung vom 20. Juni 1960 (zu Drucksache 1602) zur Sanierung der Bundesbahn, 1961; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Notes: 1 February 1961
- Box: 1, Folder: 18, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: ber Freiheit Demokratie Menschenwrde, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Author: Gustav Pietsch
    Notes: 27 February 1955
  - Item 2: Untertan der Obrigkeit, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 3: 40 Stunden sind genug, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 4: Wirtschaftspolitik im Zeichen der Strukturvernderungen, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 5: 10 Jahre Aufbau der Gewerkschaften in Bielefeld, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 6: Zur gewerkschaftlichen Situation, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Notes: 4 December 1955
- Box: 1, Folder: 19, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Das Aktions-programm, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Author: Otto Brenner
    Notes: 1-6 October 1956
  - Item 2: Die Angestellten im Zeitalter der Automation, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Author: Martin Lohmann
    Notes: 9 June 1956
  - Item 3: Gewerkschaft als Lebenselement der Modernen Gesellschaft, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Item 4: Satzung, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Item 5: Die Sicherung des Beamten in unserer Zeit, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Notes: 20-21 March 1956
  - Item 6: Zusammenstellung der Entschlieungen der Kongresse von Mnchen, Essen, Berlin, Frankfurt/M., 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Notes: July 1956
- Box: 1, Folder: 20, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: Erklrung des Deutschen Gewerkschaftsbundes zur Bundestagswahl, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Notes: 13-14 August 1957
  - Item 2: Gemeineigentum in Gegenwart und Zukunft, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Notes: October 1957
  - Item 3: Gutachten, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Author: Wilhelm Bischof
  - Item 4: Kern-Energie im Dienste der Menschheit, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Notes: 2 November 1957
- Box: 1, Folder: 21, Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Produktivitt Lohn Arbeitszeit, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Author: Bruno Gleitze
    Notes: 25-26 January 1957
  - Item 2: Werbe-Helfer, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Item 3: 1. mai, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Item 4: Wirtschaftliche, soziale und sozialmedizinische Probleme der Atomenergie, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Item 5: Wohnungspolitische Leitstze, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Item 6: Von der UGO bis zum DGB, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Box: 1, Folder: 22, Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: Arbeitnehmer und Automation, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Notes: 23-24 January 1958
  - Item 2: Arbeit und Leben, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Item 3: Entwicklung der CGD in Bayern, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Notes: 1 August 1958
  - Item 4: Fr gleichberechtigte Mitbestimmung im Handwerk, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Notes: 12 October 1958
- Box: 1, Folder: 23, Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: Konzentration Wirtschaftlicher Macht Soziale Demontage, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Notes: 20 November 1958
  - Item 2: Kritische Betrachtungen der Fernsehsendungen am 30. April 1958, Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Notes: 30 April 1958
  - Item 3: Strukturelle Vernderungen in der Wirtschaft und ihre Wirkungen, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Author: Wilhelm Haferkamp
  - Item 4: Vorschlge des DGB zur nderung des Personalvertretungsgesetzes fr das Land Nordrhein-Westfalen, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Notes: 28 May 1958
  - Item 5: Zahle dem Finanzamt nicht mehr als Du mut, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Box: 1, Folder: 24, Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Item 1: Anhang, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Notes: September 1959
  - Item 2: Bedeutung und Aufgabe der Gruppe in der industriellen Gesellschaft, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Author: Adolf Mller
  - Item 3: Berlin Bleibt Frei, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Item 4: Gewerkschaften heute und morgen, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Notes: 7-12 September 1959
  - Item 5: Das gewerkschaftliche Aktionsprogramm, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Item 6: Gewerkschaftliche Beitrge zur Frauen-erwerbsarbeit, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Box: 1, Folder: 25, Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Item 1: Hnde weg vom Gemeineigentum, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Item 2: Handwerkskammer und Lehrlingsvergtung, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Author: Karl August Bettermann
  - Item 3: Statuten des Deutschen Musikerverbandes in der Gewerkschaft Kunst, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Notes: 25 March 1959
  - Item 4: Stellungnahme zum entwurf eines niederschsischen beamtengesetzes, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Notes: 10 June 1959
  - Item 5: Strukturelle Vernderungen in der Wirtschaft und ihre Wirkungen, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Item 6: Die Verwaltung im Sozialstaat - Rckblick und Ausblick, Die Gewerkschaften und ihre Bedeutung in Staat und Gesellschaft, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Author: Josef-Hermann Dufhues, Adolf Mller
    Notes: 6 October 1959
- Box: 1, Folder: 26, Publication (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Item 1: Vorschlge des Deutschen Gewerkschaftsbundes Landesbezirk Nordrhein-Westfalen zur Neuordnung des Landesbesoldungsrechts, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Notes: March 1959
  - Item 2: Vorschlge des Deutschen Gewerkschaftsbundes Landesbezirk Nordrhein-Westfalen zur Newurdnung des Landesbesoldungsrechts, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Notes: December 1959
  - Item 3: Wirtschaftspolitik als Aufgabe, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Item 4: Zur notwendigkeit einer gesetzlichen Krankenhausplanung und Krankenhausfinanzierung, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Box: 1, Folder: 27, Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Item 1: Die Angestellten in der Rentenversicherung, Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Item 2: Mitbestimmung in der Praxis, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Item 3: Entwurf zu einem Berufsausbildungsgesetz, Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Item 4: Erklrung des Deutschen Gewerkschaftsbundes zur Bundestagswahl, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Item 5: Erste Hilfe, Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Item 6: Fr und wider: die Mitbestimmung der Arbeitnehmer in der Wirtschaft, Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Item 7: Gewerkschaften im Streit der Meinungen, Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Author: Matthias Fcher
  - Item 8: Gewerkschaftliche Beitrge zu Fragen der Berufsbildung, Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Item 9: Jugend-Sozial-Programm im Aktions-Programm des DGB, Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Box: 1, Folder: 28, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Item 1: Das kann jedem passieren!, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Item 2: Entwurf Kulturpolitische Grundstze des Deutschen Gewerkschaftsbundes, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Item 3: Merkbltter fr Jugendarbeit im Detuschen Gewerkschaftsbund, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Item 4: Mit uns in die Zukunft!, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Item 5: Schulungs und Bildungshilfen, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Item 6: Entwurf Sozialpolitische Grundstze des Deutschen Gewerkschaftsbundes, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Item 7: Das Urteil von Karlsruhe ber die Verfassungsbeschwerde von Beamten gegen das Gesetz zu Art. 131 GG, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Item 8: Was sind Gewerkschaften?, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Author: August Enderle
  - Item 9: Werbe-Helfer, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Item 10: Werkmeister Vorbildung Fortbildung, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Item 11: Wir haben darber nachgedacht und du?, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Item 12: Zur Angestelltenversicherung, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Box: 1, Folder: 29, Publication (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Item 1: In 8 Monaten 9 Flle, 1960; Publication (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Notes: 28 January - 23 September 1960
  - Item 2: Aktienrechtsreform und Mitbestimmung, 1960; Publication (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Item 3: Bemerkungen des DGB zum Entwurf eines Gesetzes zur nderung des Einkommensteuergesetzes, des Krperschaftsteuergesetzes, des Gewerbesteuergesetzes und des Wohnungsbau- Prmiengesetzes, 1960; Publication (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Notes: May 1960
  - Item 4: Die Frauenerwerbsarbeit und ihre Bedeutung in der Gegenwart, 1960; Publication (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Author: Helge Pross
    Notes: 14-15 May 1960
  - Item 5: Freizeit ist Freiheit: Sport macht sie schner!, 1960; Publication (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Box: 1, Folder: 30, Publication (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Item 1: Richtlinien fr Tarifprobleme der Angestellten, 1960; Publication (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Item 2: Schtzt die Demokratie, 1960; Publication (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Item 3: Stellungnahme zu dem auf Grund des Brand-Gutachtens erlassenen Sofortprogramm der Bundesregierung vom 20. Juni 1960 (zu Drucksache 1602) zur Sanierung der Bundesbahn, 1961; Publication (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Item 4: Ein Urteil fr die Demokratie, 1960; Publication (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Item 5: 10 Jahre Bildungsarbeit in den Bundesschulen, 1961; Publication (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Box: 1, Folder: 31, Publication (Box 1, Folder 31)